Guide to the Louise Seaman Bechtel Papers, 1877-1980 (bulk 1913-1980)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES IV. PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
  - MASSEE, May
    - Memorial material including obituary, Massee Collection Dedication Program and Bookmark, also correspondencefrom Mildred Batchelder regarding May Massee, 1966, 1972 (Folder 56.896)
  - MAXWELL, Violet and Helen Hill (See Hill)
  - MILHOUS, Katherine
    - Published print, n.d. (Folder 57.897)
  - MORVINOFF, Nicolas
    - Christmas cards, 1954-1957 (Folder 57.898)
  - MORLEY, Christopher
    - Correspondence, including a letter to H.S. Latham regarding LSB (see postscript) article, 1963, n.d. (Folder 57.899)
  - MORRISON, Lucille
    - Correspondence (Folder 57.900)
  - MORROW, Elizabeth
    - Correspondence, photograph, 1950 (Folder 57.901)
    - Photograph, n.d. (Folder 57.902)
  - MORSE, Reba
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Folder 57.903)
  - MUSSELMAN, Elaine
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 57.904)
  - NASH, Hope and Ray
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 57.905)
  - NEFF, Priscilla Holton
    - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Folder 57.906)
  - NESBITT, Elizabeth
    - Correspondence, article, 1954-1960, n.d. (Folder 57.907)
  - NEWMAN, Daisy
    - Correspondence (Folder 57.908)
  - NICHOLS, Walter
    - Correspondence, 1924 (Folder 57.909)
  - OGDEN, C. K.
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 57.910)
  - OVERTON, Jacqueline
    - Correspondence including invitation to exhibit (Folder 57.911)
  - PAROISSIEN, Harry (See also LANE, Allen.)
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Folder 57.912)
  - PAXTON, Avis Meigs
    - Correspondence, 1948 (Folder 57.913)
  - PHELPS, William Lyon
    - Correspondence, correspondence about LSB, Photograph, ca. 1918-1919, n.d. (Folder 57.914)
  - PLOTZ, Helen
    - Correspondence, Christmas cards, 1955-1956, n.d. (Folder 57.915)
  - POGANY, Willy
    - Holiday card, n.d. (Folder 57.916)
  - POOLE, Earl and Helen
    - Holiday cards with enclosed drawings and photographs, exhibition listing, 1966 (Folder 57.917)
  - PERMONT, Alphonse
    - Correspondence (in French), 1931 (Folder 57.918)
    - Notes by LSB - notes found with letters from Madame Alphonse (Folder 57.919)
  - PROSKAUER, Joseph
    - Correspondence (w/article), 1964-1967 (Folder 58.920)
  - QUAINTANCE, Charlotte
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 58.921)
  - REID, Helen
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Folder 58.922)
  - REILLY, Dorry
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Folder 58.923)
  - ROBBINS, Christine and Willie
    - Correspondence (Folder 58.924)
  - ROBINSON, Boardman (Mike) and Sally
    - Correspondence, Christmas cards, article, comprehensive exhibition guide, photograph and postcard, ca. 1916, 1943, 1978, n.d. (Folder 58.925)
  - ROBINSON, Edward Arlington
    - Correspondence, articles, photographs, LSB's notes (Folder 58.926)
  - ROBINSON, Mabel Louise
    - Correspondence (from Punch to Mr. Winkle), article, 1932, 1962 (Folder 58.927)
  - ROGERS, Bruce
    - 4 Photographs, n.d. (Folder 58.928)
  - SACKVILLE-WEST, Victoria
    - Correspondence, articles, photo mounting cardboard (photo is missing), 1962 (Folder 58.929)
  - SANDOZ, Mari
    - Correspondence, 1941 (Folder 58.930)
  - SARTON, May
    - Correspondence, article, LSB's notes, 1955, 1959 (Folder 58.931)
  - SAVAGE, Jill
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Folder 58.932)
  - SCHOLTZ, Betty
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 58.933)
  - SCHORR, Esther
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Folder 58.934)
  - SCOTT, Bill
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 58.935)
  - SEAMAN, Mary Lott (sister)
    - Correspondence, Christmas card, LSB's notes of books given to her by MLS, article, typed manuscript of story by MLS, codicil to MLS's will, letter from cousin, 1924, 1944, 1957, 1975 n.d. (Folder 58.936)
  - SHERWOOD, Margaret
    - Notes by LSB, n.d. (Folder 58.937)
  - SHOREMATOFF, Nina and Nurd
    - Christmas cards, 1968 (Folder 58.938)
  - SIMON, Jay
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Folder 58.939)
  - SIMON, Viscont John
    - Correspondence, articles, 1948, 1954 (Folder 58.940)
  - SITWELL, Osbert
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Folder 58.941)
  - SKIFF, Margaret
    - Correspondence, Christmas cards, 1971-1975 (Folder 58.942)
  - SKINNER, Constance Lindsay
    - Correspondence, LSB notes and info about, info from M. Batchelder about CLS, article, momento on the occasion of the presentation of the CLS award, photographs, 1939, 1958, 1967, n.d. (Folder 59.943)
  - SNEDEKER, Caroline
    - Correspondence, Christmas cards, photographs, 1949-1954, n.d. (Folder 59.944)
  - SPAIN, Frances Lander
    - Correspondence, 1960 (Folder 59.945)
  - STAFFORD, Elizabeth
    - Correspondence, article, 1972, n.d. (Folder 59.946)
  - STEARNS, Martha
    - Correspondence, 1962 (Folder 59.947)
  - STEELE, William
    - Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Folder 59.948)
  - STEINBERG, Saul
    - Christmas cards, 1945-1949 (Folder 59.949)
  - STEPHENS, James
    - Small book on his life, The Outcast, poem, articles, 1925, n.d. (Folder 59.950)
  - STUART, Sir Cambell
    - Correspondence, n.y. (Folder 59.951)
  - TEE-VAN, John and Helen
    - Christmas cards, invitation, article, ca. 1927, 1940-1967 (Folder 59.952)
  - TENGGREN, Gustaf
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 59.953)
  - TOLSOY, Signe
    - Correspondence, 1938 (Folder 59.954)
  - TOWNSEND, Lee
    - Correspondence, 1948 (Folder 59.955)
  - TREBLE, Arthur
    - Correspondence, 1953 (Folder 59.956)
  - TRILLING, Lionel
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Folder 59.957)
  - TUNIS, John
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Folder 59.958)
  - VAN BRUNT, Catherine
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Folder 59.959)
  - VAN BRUNT, Jessie
    - Articles, 1947 (Folder 59.960)
  - VAN CLEVE, Claudia
    - Christmas card, n.d. (Folder 60.961)
  - VAN DOREN, Irita
    - Correspondence, article, 1962, 1963 (Folder 60.962)
  - VAN DOREN, Mark
    - Article, 1932 (Folder 60.963)
  - WALL, Mildred
    - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Folder 60.964)
  - WATERMAN, Alan and Mary
    - Correspondence, article by, articles about, 1965-1975 (Folder 60.965)
  - WATSON, Helen
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Folder 60.966)
  - WELLES, Winifred
    - Correspondence, poem, published poem, 1933, 1962, n.d. (Folder 60.967)
  - WHITNEY, Elinor
    - Correspondence (Folder 60.968)
  - WIESE, Kurt and Gertrud [See also Series VI for artwork by Kurt Wiese.]
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Folder 60.969)
  - WILKINSON, Marguerite
    - Correspondence, 1923 (Folder 60.970)
  - WOODWARD, Hildegard
    - Christmas card, 1933 (Folder 60.971)
  - WRIGHT, Anna Maria
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Folder 60.972)
  - WYLIE, Laura
    - Correspondence and LSB's notes, 1918 (Folder 60.973)
  - YEATS, William Butler
    - Correspondence, ca. 1921 (Folder 60.974)
    - LSB transcription of WBY's letter, articles, 1963-1975, n.d. (Folder 60.975)
  - ZIEGLER, Fran
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Folder 60.976)
  - MISCELLANEOUS Personal Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1922-1975, n.d. (Folder 60.977)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Folder 60.978)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Folder 60.979)
- SERIES V. PERSONAL AND FAMILY MATERIALS
  - Personal Materials
    - Vassar College syllabus for economics, 1913 (Folder 61.980)
    - Vassar College textbooks and bibliography, 1900-1913 (Folder 61.981)
    - Vassar College Class of 1915 "War Reunion" bulletin, 1943 (Folder 61.982)
    - Vassar College Class of 1915 reunion materials, 1965, 1975 (Folder 61.983)
    - Vassar College pamphlets, 1921-1970 (Folder 61.984)
    - Travel log of LSB's first European trip, 1926 (Folder 61.985)
    - Clippings and invitation re: the Bechtels' rose garden, 1962, 1965, 1972 (Folder 62.986)
    - Bedford Garden Club materials, ca. 1940-1959 (Folder 62.987)
    - Annual report of the Bedford Garden Club, 1938-1939 (Folder 62.988)
    - Annual report of the Bedford Garden Club, 1939-1940 (Folder 62.989)
    - Annual report of the Bedford Garden Club, LSB, president with her report and clippings, 1941-1942 (Folder 62.990)
    - Articles on flowers by LSB, 1952, 1956 (Folder 62.991)
    - Personal, miscellaneous materials, n.d. (Folder 62.992)
  - Family Material
    - Marriage announcement of Louise Seaman and Edwin de Turck Bechtel with related Correspondence, 1929 (Folder 62.993)
    - Materials relating to Edwin de Turck Bechtel, 1940, 1960, n.d. (Folder 62.994)
    - Contents of scrapbook created by Charles F. Seaman, LSB's father, folder 1 of 2, 1877-1941 (Folder 62.995)
    - Contents of scrapbook created by Charles F. Seaman, LSB's father, folder 2 of 2 [See also Seaman scrapbook, box 75.], 1877-1941 (Folder 62.996)
- SERIES VI. ARTWORK
  - ANDERSEN, Hans Christian
    - Etching of his house in Copenhagen, 1928 (Framed)
  - ARTZYBASHEFF, Boris
    - Print done for The Fairy Shoemaker; signed, n.d.; (10 ¾" x 14 1/8") (Framed)
    - Woodcut done for The Fairy Shoemaker—a child in bed; signed, 1929; (10 ½" x 12 ½") (Framed)
    - Woodcut done for The Fairy Shoemaker—woman, house, and dog; signed, 1929; (10 ½" x 12 ½") (Framed)
  - BECHTEL, Louise Seaman
    - Photographic portrait, n.d.; (14 ½" x 16 ½") (Framed)
  - BIANCO, Pamela
    - Figure of woman surrounded by foliage; signed, 1928; (5" x 9 ½") (Box 76)
    - Bouquet; inscribed, "For Louise Seaman, with greetings from Pamela, 1927; ("7" x 11 ½") (Box 76)
    - Houseplant; signed, n.d.; (8 ¾" x 14") (Box 76)
  - BUCKLEY, Alec
    - Woodcut, "Music and Bells," no. 26 of 50 copies, (9 ½" x 11 ½" and 3" x 3 7/8") (Framed)
  - COATSWORTH, Elizabeth
    - Photographic portrait by Jan Leigt, early 1920s; (11 ½" x 13 ¼") (Framed)
  - EICHENBERG, Fritz
    - Christmas card, "The Peaceable Kingdom,", 1960; (9" x 12 ½") (Box 76)
    - Wood-engraving, "The Peaceable Kingdom;" signed; in folder with printed description, 1950; (14" x 19" and 5" x 7 ½") (Framed)
  - FRASER, C. Lovat
    - Rhyme Sheet, “Meeting Mary,” poem by Eleanor Farjeon, n.d.; (14” x 7”) (Mapcase — Drawer 36)
  - GUTZLAFF, Lotte
    - Silhouette of child with toy driving goat cart; signed; given to LSB by Peggy King when LSB accepted offer to be editor of Macmillan's children's book dept., n.d.; (6 ¼" x 10") (Framed)
  - GUTH, Arnold
    - Pair of paintings from The Little Christmas Story, n.d.; (10 ½" x 14 1/3" and 7" x 11") (Framed)
  - HAGREEN, Philip
    - Rhyme Sheet, n.d.; (22 ¼” x 8 ½”) (Mapcase — Drawer 36)
  - HANDFORTH, Thomas
    - Etching, "Old Chinese Scholar;" signed, n.d.; (9 7/8" x 15") (Framed)
  - KING, Margaret (Peggy) Pinckney Allen [wife of Stanley King, president of Amherst College]
    - Photographic portrait, n.d.; (9" x 11 ¼") (Framed)
  - LATHROP, Dorothy P.
    - Woodcut, "Efts,", 1933; (9 1/8" x 9 1/8" and 3 ¾" x 3 ¼") (Framed)
    - Woodcut, "Leopard Frog,", 1932; (11 ½" x 11 ½") (Framed)
    - Woodcut for The Light Princess, "They found the princess under a rosebush;" signed, (9" x 9" and 3 1/8" x 2 ½") (Framed)
    - Woodcut, "Spriggen"[DPL's dog and her first woodcut], 1928; (8 7/8" x 12 ¾") (Framed)
    - Woodcut of tropical fish printed for Albany Print Club; signed, n.d.; (16 ½" x 19 3/8") (Framed)
    - Pen and ink sketch with watercolor, a valentine, ca. 1931; (9 ¾" x 11 7/8") (Framed)
    - LATHROP, Dorothy P.: "Italian Greyhound"; signed "To Louise Seaman Bechtel with love from DPL,", (6 ½" x 7 ¾") (Box 76)
    - "Mao T'ou Ying"; signed "To Louise Bechtel on Valentine's Day,", n.d.; (5" x 5 ½") (Box 76)
    - "The Secret Place"; signed, "To Louise Bechtel with love and best wishes,", Feb 1961; (4" x 4") (Box 76)
    - Hitty and squirrel; signed, "For Louise, inspiring editor, with love and gratitude from Hitty and Dorothy,", (4 ½ x 6") (Box 76)
  - LEIGHTON, Clare
    - "Blackbird on Nest"; signed, n.d.; (4 ½" x 7") (Box 76)
    - Woodcut, "Lambing," no. 15 of 20 (second state), (16" x 22" and 8" x 10 3/8") (Framed)
  - MACKINSTRY, Elizabeth
    - Print of a man in uniform. "In honour of a Reunion 1933 - Dec. 6,", n.d.; (11 ¾" x 15 ¼") (Framed)
  - MARSHALL, Rachel
    - The Rhyme Sheet, Poem by Jane and Ann Taylor, (32” x 8”) (Mapcase — Drawer 36)
  - McNAB, Alvan
    - Pen and ink drawing of sailing ships in Mediterranean [?] harbor, 1930?; (17 ½" x 24 ½") (Framed)
  - MELDRUM, Roy
    - The Lion and the Unicorn, (24” x 8”) (Mapcase — Drawer 36)
  - POTTER, Beatrix
    - Drawing of mouse and teacup from The Tailor of Gloucester, Nov 1927; (9 ½" x 12 ½" and 5" x 7") (Framed)
  - PYLE, Howard
    - 1st proof of a picture for King Arthur; inscribed and signed, Oct 1907; (11 ½" x 14" and 4" x 6 ¼") (Framed)
  - SEWELL, Helen
    - "Some keep the Sabbath going to church - E. Dickinson,", n.d.; (5" x 6") (Box 76)
    - "Daphne"; signed, n.d.; (5" x 7") (Box 76)
    - "Subway"; signed, n.d.; (5" x 5") (Box 76)
    - "Clinic"; signed, n.d.; (7" x 9") (Box 76)
    - Early woodcut, hand-colored on the back of old Christmas card (Box 76)
  - STEWART, Bert
    - Pencil drawing, "Mr. Winkel [sic] dozes off!,", 1932; (12" x 15") (Framed)
  - VAN LOON, Hendrik Willem
    - Get-well card (in 3 pieces) for LSB after falling and breaking her hip, "To Our Fallen Sister,", 1932; (13" x 22") (Box 76)
  - WARD, Lynd
    - Woodcut, "Bouquet"; inscribed, n.d.; (14" x 20") (Framed)
    - Woodcut, "Clouded Over; For Louise and Ned Bechtel - in high regard,", 1948; (15 3/8" x 20 ½" and 6" x 9") (Framed)
  - WIESE, Kurt
    - Linoleum cut of a fawn, [1933]; (10 3/8" x 13 3/8") (Framed)
    - Etching, "Zebras"; inscribed to LSB and signed, (14" x 15 1/8") (Framed)
  - WINZER, Charles
    - “Rhyme Sheet” Poems by Harold Monroe, n.d.; (22 ½” x 8”) (Mapcase — Drawer 36)
- SERIES VII. OVERSIZED MATERIAL
  - Professional and Publishing Material Scrapbooks
    - "The Book of Louise Seaman Bechtel at Work," (Box 63)
    - Bechtel Herald Tribune children's book reviews: "Book I,", 1949 (Box 64)
    - Bechtel Herald Tribune children's book reviews: "Book II,", 1950-1951 (Box 65)
    - Bechtel Herald Tribune children's book reviews: "Book III,", 1951-1952 (Box 66)
    - Bechtel Herald Tribune children's book reviews: "Book IV,", 1953 (Box 67)
    - Bechtel Herald Tribune children's book reviews: "Book V,", 1954 (Box 68)
    - Bechtel Herald Tribune children's book reviews: "Book VI,", 1955 (Box 69)
    - New York Herald Tribune Book Review, Spring and Fall issues, 1950-1955 (Box 70)
    - New York Herald Tribune Children's Book Festival announcements (Box 71)
    - "Classics"—material on literature, authors, illustrators, publishing (Box 72)
    - "Horse and Dog" (Boxes 73-74)
  - Family Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbook of Charles F. Seaman (Box 75)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs
    - Photograph of and inscribed to LSB by Lynd Ward (Folder 76.997)
    - Photo of LSB and staff at Macmillan. [From print at U. of FL] (Folder 76.997a)
    - Photographs relating to the 1941 Writers' Conference in Colorado (Folder 76.998)
    - Miscellaneous photographs (Folder 76.999)
    - Miscellaneous printed materials, including Paget-Fredericks' inscribed program of "Song of the Troubador" (1959) and a Parisian dinner menu from LSB's trip in 1926 (Folder 76.1000)
  - Children's Amusements
    - "Our Little Doll's House": album with different rooms and movable figures drawn by Else Weng-Vietor (Box 77)
    - The Golden Christmas Manger, illustrated by Helen Sewell [2 sets], 1948 (Box 78)
    - Bust of Mr. Nathaniel Winkle [the Bechtel's dachshund] (Folder 79.1001)
    - French coloring books, 1940s (Folder 79.1002)
    - Advent calendar: "Enid Blyton's Christmas Story," illustrated by Fritz Wegner (Folder 79.1003)
    - Antique greeting cards [2], n.d. (Folder 79.1004)
    - Jigsaw puzzle: Beatrix Potter's The Tailor of Gloucester (Folder 79.1005)